what do you feel helps the most with
weight that creeps up during perian
menopause yeah typical question there oh
gosh I know this is a really really
really tough one right well so I think
like you know the the obvious answer
right the obvious answer or the easy
answer um would be you know glp1
agonists which everybody is taking now I
don't I don't know that that's that's
the right answer though but I'll I'll
start there so so I don't know what's
going on in Europe but here in America
every is crazy for OIC and mararo uh the
drugs of course are semaglutide and
tepati and these are glp1 agonists that
they're developed as diabetic drugs but
of course they cause a lot of weight
loss and so everybody is taking them
everyone is crazy for them and we have
them compounded so the it's you know
they're more affordable and they will
definitely make you lose weight but
again
I like if if you're like an obese
diabetic of course right and when and
when people ask me for the drugs
regardless when people ask me I I will
give them right I don't deny them to
anybody but
honestly what what really I think is a
better long-term solution than these
drugs is getting your hormones balanced
for sure um and and then honestly you
have to just really you have to tighten
up your diet you have to start keeping
track of what you're eating and and I
know like I myself struggle with this
but you have to keep track of what
you're eating and and get an
understanding of how many calories
you're actually taking in to make sure
you get a ton of protein a gram per uh
lean body mass or or per ideal body
weight at least and exercise a ton of
exercise and a lot of women say that
they're just too tired to exercise and
again that can be fixed with with
hormones with supplements with a diet a
healthier diet can give you more energy
so you can exercise I mean the weight is
just such a complicated thing I think I
think we have
76% or 73 73 or 76% of America is
overweight now and a a big chunk of
those are actually obese and and it's a
huge problem and again I'm not I'm not
against the glp1 agonists but you know
you you go off you gain the weight back
and like unless you want to stay on one
of these drugs for the rest of your life
you have to buckle down and really work
on your lifestyle mhm here in Belgium at
least we don't have the compounded
versions of those um we only have OIC it
has become very popular as well the last
few years even so popular that now it's
forbidden for us doctors to prescribe it
if the patient is not diabetic really
really and what it comes from Denmark
right though so like you're you're
pretty close you're closer than we are
to Denmark yeah um I was reading
actually that that this is like a huge
Factor now in Denmark's economy they've
made so much money from from these
drugs
yeah so people aren't using it there for
weight loss yeah people were using it
for weight loss and I've prescribed it
several patients as well but since a few
months uh it's forbidden to prescribe it
uh if it's not if it's not for a
diabetic patient so uh why why because
there's a shortage or yeah because
there's a shortage yeah that's the why
so it's so crazy
and like look like everybody wants a
quick fix and an easy way to lose weight
and and I totally get that you know um
but it's I just don't it's not a great
long-term solution I don't know what do
you think yeah I don't know uh that that
was actually my question because I don't
have a lot of experience with it uh do
patients that have lost a lot of weight
with it do they have to continue
indefinitely can they stop or do they
rebounds then so okay so this is my
experience and again I mean you know
it's it's from a couple of years right
like because they're new drugs but if
you are on a significant dose of of
either semaglutide or tepati and you
just stop you will have a lot of
cravings and you will gain the weight
back so you can I recommend doing a slow
taper to come off of it really slowly
and that definitely helps and then I
have a lot of patients that like you
know they've lost the weight and they've
they've cut down to like a pretty low
dose but they are doing something for
maintenance and whether it's like you
know like a low dose once every other
week or like you know whatever it is
like like not not a not a full dose
every week whatever they were on to lose
the weight but they're there is some
some rebound waking and it's not like a
it's because these Cravings come back
and and that appetite suppression that
you rely on is gone and so then people
eat and uh so so I I mean I have a lot
of facei that they do take a low dose
every couple of weeks and I mean maybe
that's for life you know but I I don't
know again I'm not I'm not like against
it but I'm I'm not really for
it do you have any experience with the
oral versions like Rebels because those
we can still
prescribe no I don't think we have that
here what is
it it's um like OIC but the oral version
It's called Rebus um it's also expensive
but there's not a shortage yet so we can
still prescribe those for overweight
patients no I only have experience with
the injectable drugs how uh tell me
about your experience how do how does it
work does it work well no I I don't know
yet since it's only a few months that
it's forbidden for overweight patients
that are not diabetic I switch the
patients to the oral version but it's
only a few months so I I can't keep I
can't um estimate the the progression
not yet okay well let me know and I'll
look into it and see if we can get it
here I mean everyone is just using the
injectables yeah probably yeah I find it
a strange thing um yeah I'll I'll send
you the I'll send you the link how it's
called what we can prescribe here yeah
yeah so we have like so we use at the
Medical Health Institute we use
compounded products and it is pretty
easy to get the compounded products from
a variety of pharmacies and so that and
it's cheaper and that gets around any
kind of manufacturer shortage of the
brand names yeah um yeah Rebel is also
semaglutide but just the oral version
okay yeah I have to look into it yeah we
we only use the
injectable
[Music]